# 大家好 今天去摘點這個
Hi everyone! Today we're gonna pick some, you know,
# 這個枇杷哦 這是兄弟家的
some loquats. They are at my buddy's place.
# 你看 我們都跑到廣東這邊來的
Look! We've come to Guangdong.
# 你看 這棟房子就是兄弟家的
Look! This is my buddy's flat.
# 以前我們跟他都是鄰居來的
We used to be neighbours.
# 他現在都搬到廣東這邊來啦
But now he has moved here to Guangdong.
# 你看 他家的枇杷果
Look! These are his loquats.
# 那麼多他都不摘
There are so many, but he's not picking them.
# 剛好今天他不在喲 我幫它摘
It just so happens that he's not around today. I can help him.
# 一樹都是
They're all over the tree.
# 哇 這個樹好上
Wa! What an easy climb!
# 直接踩上來都就可以了啦
Step on it, and I'm in right away.
# 摘多一點回去
Pick more, won't you?
# 接著
Catch it!
# 啊 沒有接到
Ah! I couldn't.
# 沒接到哇
You couldn't catch?
# 嗯 我還沒過來呢
Um! I'm still coming , you know.
# 看 看到沒有
Can, can you see it now?
# 你看到啦
Now I can.
# 拿到啦
It's in my hands now.
# 好啦 好啦 夠啦
Alright, alright! It's enough.
# 吃到你們牙酸都有啦
There are enough to make your teeth fatigue.
# 你看 就摘了這幾個
Look! I've just picked a few here.
# 嗯 這枇杷好啦
Um! This loquat is really tasty.
# 很好肉 你看 肉是白色的
It's so rich. Look! The pulp is white.
# 啊 熟過頭啦
Ah! It's too ripe.
# 好不好看
Does it look good?
# 帶回去哦
I'll bring them back.
# 把樹技割斷了一點
I've chopped some of the branches.
# 沒辦法
Well, anyway,
# 我太重啦
I'm too heavy,
# 我它樹枝壓斷啦
and these branches couldn't stand my weight.
# 收工 收工
Let's go, let's go!
# 這邊還有 全部撒到地上啦
Some more here. They were all splashed onto the ground.
# 走啦
Let's go!